Guide to the Urodynamics Society records, 1967-1999 and undated RL.01324
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Urodynamics Society records
1967-1999 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Urodynamics Society
RL.01324
2.0 Linear Feet
Collection houses records regarding the history of the Urodynamics Society, currently known as the Society of Urodynamics, Female Pelvic Medicine, and Urogenital Reconstruction (SUFU), whose first president and founder (1978-1979) was Dr. Saul Boyarsky, physician and faculty member at Duke University, and donor of the collection. File contents include correspondence relating to the Society's activities and development, chiefly during the 1980s, and the transfer of the collection to the Duke Medical Center Library; several booklets with the Society's membership lists, constitution and by-laws, from 1978 to 1982 and 1993; printed articles and abstracts concerning the history of urodynamics; a bibliography of literature in the field (1990-1991); Dr. Boyarsky's notes and a long published article on the history of the Society (1999); Dr. Luis Perez's published article on the history of urodynamics (1992), with comments and a draft; and other small items. Acquired as part of the History of Medicine Collections at Duke University.
Approx. 900 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Urodynamics Society records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2011.
Historical Note
The Urodynamics Society, currently known as the Society of Urodynamics, Female Pelvic Medicine, and Urogenital Reconstruction (SUFU), is an organization concerned with providing research and training in urology and urodynamics. It is currently based in Missouri. Its first president and founder (1978-1979) was Dr. Saul Boyarsky, donor of the collection and former faculty member at Duke University, later at Washington University in Missouri.
Collection Overview
File contents include correspondence relating to the Society's activities and development, chiefly during the 1980s, and the transfer of the collection to the Duke Medical Center Library; several booklets with the Society's membership lists, constitution and by-laws, from 1978 to 1982 and 1993; printed articles and abstracts concerning the history of urodynamics; a bibliography of literature in the field (1990-1991); Dr. Boyarsky's notes and a long published article on the history of the Society (1999); Dr. Luis Perez's published article on the history of urodynamics (1992), with comments and a draft; and other small items. Acquired as part of the History of Medicine Collections at Duke University.
Urology -- History; Medicine -- Societies, etc.; Urodynamics Society; Urodynamics Society; History of Medicine Collections (Duke University); Boyarsky, Saul
- Urodynamics Society records, 1967-1999 and undated, 4 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1967-1996, 25 folders (Box 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1999 (Box 4)
  - Bank accounts, 1976-1980 (Box 3)
  - Constitution, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 3)
  - History: Urodynamics Society reminiscences, (paper, 1999) by Saul Boyarsky, M.D., 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Membership lists, 1969-1979 and undated (Box 3)
  - Membership lists, articles of incorporation, and bylaws, 1980-1982, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Printed materials, 1970-1982 and undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Printed materials: compendium of urodynamics literature for 1990-1991, published 1993 (Box 4)
  - Printed materials: The history of urodynamics, article by Luis M. Perez, M.D. (1992), with comments and a draft, 1991-1992 (Box 4)